J.R. STRAYHORN

1293 Spring Park Walk, Cincinnati, OH 513-291-3361 • jrstrayhorn@gmail.com

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL STACK) - ANGULAR AND .NET CORE

Certified Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience looking for a hands-on Senior Development role. I have worked in a variety of environments, performing all manner of web development pivoting from Web Forms to SharePoint before focusing on modern Full Stack solutions using Angular and .NET Core, skills including:

- ASP.NET and .NET Core Development using C#
- API Development against SQL and NoSQL DBs
- Agile Development Practices (Scrum) in Sprints
- Technical Consulting, Customer-Facing, Training
- Unit Testing Angular and .NET

- Angular and TypeScript Development
- Cloud (Azure, AWS, Google, DigitalOcean)
- Technical Leadership (Teams, Mentoring)
- CI/CD on Azure DevOps with Git
- Communication Skills (Written/Verbal)

WORK EXPERIENCE

AssureCare LLC. 2018 to 2020

Senior Software Engineer / Team Lead / Manager

- **Full Stack Development:** Designed, developed, and maintained health care application/product using C#, .NET 4.5+, .NET Core, HTML5, Angular, Angular Material, Bootstrap, CSS3, RESTful Web APIs, ASP.NET MVC, WCF Web Services, Entity Framework, SQL Server and MongoDB.
- **Microservices Development:** Pioneered microservice development creating the first micro service integration with existing Web APIs developed with .NET Core and MongoDB hosted in Docker container deployed to Kubernetes.
- **Agile Development Practices / DevOps (CI/CD):** Participated in system design, development, testing and deployment (Azure DevOps for CI/CD) using Agile (Scrum) practices such as daily stand ups, backlog grooming, sprint planning and reviews.
- **Angular / TypeScript Development**: Assisted with creation of first reusable component library (internal) using Angular, Typescript, NX and Docker
- **Mentoring:** Mentored Jr. and Mid. level developers across the development teams

Team Lead Highlights

- **Agile Development Practices:** Led agile development team in achieving results through technical decision-making, peer code review and mentoring to ensure the team was "dev complete" by the end of the sprint.
- **Technical Leadership:** Worked with Development Manager to implement technical vision and best practices with the development team and worked with fellow developers on the team to turn it into reality.
- **Unit Testing / Communication Skills:** Led initiative to get all development teams to begin unit testing in Angular with Jest; created presentation and documentation as well.
- Mentoring / Training: Led initiative to use Pluralsight Role IQs as a tool to help developers grow and become Full Stack Developers using Angular, .NET, Entity Framework, Git, SQL Server, MongoDB and Microservices.

Manager Highlights

- **Agile Development Practices:** Worked closely with CTO to promote and provide a clear vision, strategy and implement best practices in agile software development.
- **Technical Leadership:** Led hiring initiatives through technical interviewing and screening to grow the size of global agile development teams by over 500% within a year.
- **Quality:** Established goals and monitored metrics with development teams related to code coverage, % resolution of sprint items, average days of resolution and first-time pass rate to increase quality of the product.

Total Quality Logistics, Senior Software Engineer

2020 to 2021

- Worked on upgrading out of support Front End apps from Angular v6 to v10, fixed existing unit tests, refactored to feature and feature routing modules.
- Worked on upgrading out of support Web APIs from .NET Core v2.2 to v 3.1, refactored to make all calls async and properly use DI with ILogger and IHttpClientFactory
- Created swagger documentation and Developer guides on Unit Testing.

Capgemini, Senior Consultant

2017 to 2018

- Lead developer and consultant with Sogeti USA Division on multiple projects ranging from a custom mobile app that tracks professional education to the migration of a large custom solution built on top of SharePoint
- Created custom solutions using Xamarin Forms, SharePoint, ASP.NET and jQuery

First Group America, Lead Developer

2014 to 2016

- Created custom SharePoint applications to manage business operations and equipment across all First Transit locations nationwide, and business contacts via custom CRM solution - built with C#, ASP.NET Web Forms
- Built custom UIs for Office 365 sites using JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap

KiZAN Technologies, Senior Consultant

2008 to 2014

- Created custom SharePoint solutions for Enterprise Calendaring, File Renaming and Document Publishing and Custom Accounting Approval Workflows - built with C#, JavaScript and jQuery
- Consultant on several SharePoint and Web Development Projects for small / medium / large organization across the Tri-State Area

PROJECTS

Bright Star Connect - Lead Developer

- Event Registration System (MVP) to replace current paper-based process
- Using Angular 9, .NET Core 3.1, EF Core, MailGun, mySQL and DigitalOcean for hosting
- Live site available here: https://brightstar-connect.jrstrayhorn.com

Commudle - Open Source Contributor

- Platform that organizes events for tech communities; added new feature Cookie Consent
- Used Angular 10, Typescript and Nebular Design Framework
- PRs available here: https://github.com/commudle/commudle-ng/pulls/jrstrayhorn

Code 4 Romania (Civic Tech Organization) - Open Source Contributor

- Admin app for election observations; added new features and performed bug fixes
- Used Angular 9, Typescript, .NET Core, ng-bootstrap, angular-jwt to decode JWT tokens
- PRs available here: https://github.com/code4romania/monitorizare-vot-ong/pulls/jrstrayhorn

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATION

Angular Certified Developer (Level 2) - <u>AngularTraining.com</u>, 2021 BS in Information Technology w/ College Honors - University of Cincinnati, OCAS, 2006

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Front-End Focused:** JavaScript, TypeScript, Jest, HTML5, CSS3, Angular (latest), RxJS, NgRx, Husky, Bootstrap, Angular Material, Font Awesome, JWT (decoding, storage)
- Back-End, DB Focused: C#, ASP.NET, .NET Core, EF Core, Dapper, Swagger, SQL Server, MongoDB, mySQL, NUnit, AutoMapper, JWT (creation, authentication)
- Cloud Platforms & Services: AWS, Firebase, Azure, Google Cloud, DigitalOcean, MailGun, Stripe, Twilio
- Tools: Git, Github, Azure DevOps, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio (Latest), npm, NX